Guide to the Livres d'artiste papers, 2005 - 2020 MS 990
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Livres d'artistes collection
2005-2020
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Prendeville, Jet
MS 990
1 Linear Feet 2 document boxes
The collection contains documentation of the Livres d'artistes books acquired for the Fondren Library; information on the artists who created the books; administrative records; and information on presentations/class instruction made about the collection.
Biographical / Historical
A livre d'artiste is a limited edition, handmade book combining original prints with the artist often supervising the production of the book and collaborating with the author of the text. Because many of these books are not constrained by the normal limits of a bound book, often assuming sculptural qualities, book art is perhaps a more appropriate term to use in describing these artists' books.
The original criteria for the collection was that the works were created by prominent artists and significant literary authors.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains documentation of the Livres d'artistes books acquired for the Fondren Library; information on the artists who created the books; administrative records; and information on presentations/class instruction made about the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
These materials were donated by Jet Prendeville, the retired Art and Architecture Librarian at Fondren Library.
Index Terms
Subjects
Literature
Document Types
prints (visual works)
Places
Book art; Art
- Series I: Presentations
  - Information: Printing & Rare Books, 2006-2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Friends of Fondren Board, 2007-03-15 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art of the Book Panel Symposium, 2007-09-27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ARTS 309 Print Processes & Connoisseurship, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Houston Book Arts Guild, 2012-11-01 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Printmaking Roundtable/ Exquisite Collaboration: Growing a Collection of Artist's Books, 2013-10-30 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ARTS 378 Exhibition Design, 2017-10-03 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Looking at Art, 2019-02-07 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II: Administration
  - Flyleaf Vol 56, No. 1 Article, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clamshell Boxes Carolyn Chadwick (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clamshell Boxes Wendy Ossoning (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Invoices: Devin Borden/Hiram Butler Gallery, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Invoices: Devin Borden Gallery/Brooklyn Arts Alliance, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mazur: Loan to MFAH for Exhibit, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A University Dedicated: Thomas LaVergne, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Student Portfolio: Selection Procedures (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series III: Artists
  - Amat, Frederic / Wilson, Robert (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Arp, Hans (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Beckmann, Max (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bourgeois, Louise (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Braque, Georges (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Celmins, Vija (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dill Leslie / Sleigh, Tom (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dine, Jim (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Ernst, Max (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Francis, Sam (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Francis, Sam / Ting, Walasse (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Gerzso, Gunther (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Goldberg, Glenn / Hirsch, Edward (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Hancock, Trenton Doyle (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Hardin, Thomas / Student Portfolio (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Hartigan, Grace / Schyler, James (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Hayter, Stanley William (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Holkney, David (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Hodgkin, Howard / Sontag, Susan (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Indiana, Robert / Creeley, Robert (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Jenson, Bill / Yao, John (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Johns, Jasper (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Kent, Jane / Ford, Richard (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Kentridge, William (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Matisse- Facsimile only (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Lanskoy, Andre (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Laurens, Henri (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Le Corbusier (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Leger, Fernand / Rimbaud, Arthur (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Man Ray (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Mangold, Robert / Howe, Susan (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Maret, Russell (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mazur, Michael (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Miranda, Ibrahim (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Miro, Joan / Tzara, Tristan (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Mitchell, Joan / Ashberry, John (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Moore, Henry / Auden, W. H. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Motherwell, Robert (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Murray, Elizabeth /Waldeman, Anne (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Picasso, Pablo / Balzac (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Puryear, Martin / Toomer, Jean (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Smith, Kiki / Berssenbrugge, Mei-Mei (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Stockholder, Jessica (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Turrell, James (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Tuttle, Richard (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Villon, Jacques / Virgil (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Walker, Kara / Morrison, Toni (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Waterston, Darren / Dory, Mark (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Wayne, June / Donne, John (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Winters, Terry (Box 2, Folder 30)